我能听到别人听不到的
My ears hear what others cannot hear.
能看到别人看不到的  微小的遥远的东西
Small, faraway things people cannot normally see are visible to me.
这些感知是渴望了一生的结果
These senses are the fruits of a lifetime of longing.
渴望被拯救
Longing to be rescued.
渴望被补全
To be completed.
就像渴望被风吹起的裙摆
Just as the skirt needs the wind to billow...
我并非是由我自身构成
...I'm not formed by things that are of myself alone.
我系着爸爸的腰带  穿着妈妈的上衣
I wear my father's belt tied around my mother's blouse.
鞋子是我叔叔的
And shoes which are from my uncle.
这就是我
This is me.
就像一朵花不能选择它的颜色
Just as a flower does not choose its color...
我们也无法为我们的将来负责
...we are not responsible for what we have come to be.
当你意识到这个的时候  你就自由了
Only once you realize this do you become free.
长大
And to become adult...
就自由了
...is to become free.
生日快乐
生日快乐  印蒂雅
斯托克
————translated by cheeseflower————
all rights reserved
理查德  不要
Richard! No!
一个忠于家庭的男人
A family man...
疼爱妻子伊芙琳的丈夫
...devoted husband to his wife, Evelyn...
爱护女儿印蒂雅的父亲
...loving father to his daughter, India.
他是我们镇子的楷模
He was a model to our town...
这样一个率真  正直的人
...and of what it means to be a man who walks through the world...
去了天国
...with openness, honesty and integrity.
-印蒂雅  -命运把理查德·斯托克
-India? -Richard Stoker was taken from us...
永远地带离了我们
...by a cruel twist of fate.
印蒂雅
India?
原因不明也无法理解
The reasons for which are unknown and unknowable.
一起任何人都无法预料的意外
By an accident nobody would have predicted.
哪怕是理查德这样
It would have been impossible for even an outstanding architect...
接触的建筑师
...like Richard...
也无法理解上帝的旨意
...to understand God's great design.
印蒂雅
India?
India.
客人快到了
The guests will be here soon.
你可以去厨房给加里克夫人打打下手吗
Can you help Mrs. McGarrick in the kitchen?
拜托
Please?
别这副表情  印蒂雅
Don't do this to me, India.
今天不行
Not today.
他们撬开他车的时候
When they pried open his car...
-他的尸体  -都烧焦了
-...you know, his body was burned... -To a crisp.
太可怕了
Terrible accident.
好可伶  印蒂雅和她爸爸那么亲近
Poor thing. India was so close to her father.
-谁来照顾她呀  -她还有妈妈呢
-Who's gonna look after her? -She's still got her mother.
她妈妈照顾她  得了吧
Her mother look after her? More like the other way around.
你知道吗  这起意外太奇怪了
You know what? This whole accident is so strange.
你听到传言了吗
Have you heard all the rumors floating around...?
你不觉得他本来要过桥的吗
You don't think he meant to drive off the bridge?
-为什么他要跑到两州外的地方  -不知道
-Why did he have to go two states away? -I don't know.
-还好吗  -是  加里克夫人
-Everything all right? -Yes, Mrs. McGarrick.
我怀疑是不是冰箱里放久了
Now I'm wondering if I kept them in the fridge too long.
你觉得呢  我是不是太舍不得辣椒粉了
What do you think? Was I too stingy with the paprika?
你这邪恶的鸡蛋让我想起小时候
Your deviled eggs remind me of when I was a little girl.
你也许长大了  但还是把蛋壳搞到地上去
Well, you may be all grown up, but you still get eggshells all over the floor.
你的鞋是不是小了
Have you outgrown your shoes?
你找到生日礼物没
Did you find your birthday present yet?
我找到了盒子  但里面是空的
I found the box, but it was empty.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
检查过了吗
Did you check?
再检查一次
Check again.
每年我都以为是爸爸把鞋子送给我做生日礼物
Every year I thought it was my father who left me shoes on my birthday.
但是这次
But all this time, it's been--
告诉我这是什么钥匙
Tell me what it opens.
我哪知道
How would I know?
好吧
All right.
那是我弟弟
That was my brother....
开始它们是四个
You know, originally they were part of a set of four...
但是我小时候打碎了一个
...but then I broke one as a kid.
我现在回来发现肯定有人打碎了另一个
Now I'm seeing in this house someone must have let another break.
不  不是我
No, it wasn't me.
我们搬进来时  女佣拆包裹打碎了一个
When we-- When we moved in, it broke as the housekeepers were unpacking it.
印蒂雅  过来和查理叔叔打个招呼
India. Come and say hello to your Uncle Charlie.
印蒂雅  过来
India? Come over.
待会见
See you soon.
你好  印蒂雅
Hello, India.
过来
Come on.
她不喜欢和人接触
She hates to be touched.
即便我是她妈
I'm her mother.
多古怪
What a curse.
查理  理查德以前说
You know, Charlie, Richard used to say...
我们永远找不到你了
...that we had lost you to the rest of the world forever.
印蒂雅  你怎么脸色这么差
Why, India, you're white as a sheet.
出什么事了吗
Is something wrong?
是啊
Yes.
我爸爸死了
My father is dead.
好美
How beautiful.
理查德引以为豪印蒂雅的打猎技术
Richard was so proud of India's hunting
他把她的每个猎物都制成标本
that he stuffed every single thing she killed.
真是浪费时间
What a tragic waste of life.
它们住在森林深处
These live particularly deep in the forest.
肯定很难捉到
They'd be very hard to catch.
我猜理查德和印蒂雅配合默契
I guess Richard and India were a good team.
他参加亲哥哥的葬礼居然不穿黑色  太不尊重了
It's kind of disrespectful, him not wearing black to his own brother's funeral.
他肯定刚从中东还是什么地方回来
He must have come back today from the Middle East or something.
是在伊斯坦布尔什么地方挖东西吗
It's just part of a dig in some old part of Istanbul?
不  我觉得他是在找不一样的东西  印尼黄金
No, I think he was digging for something quite different. Gold in Indonesia.
真的很感谢您今早的悼词
I really want to thank you for your words this morning.
你和理查德称得上这些
Well, you and Richard deserve every word.
酒不错
The wine's good.
你在这  来这边
There you are. Come and join us.
他是理查德的弟弟
This is Richard's brother.
你好
Hello.
-他回来了  -幸会
-He's back. -Nice to meet you.
布鲁姆夫妇是我们的好朋友
These are the Blooms, good friends of ours.
晚上好
Good evening.
我都不知道理查德还有个弟弟
I didn't know Richard had a brother.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
为你亲人的逝去  我们很遗憾
We're sorry for your loss.
你怎么认识理查德的
How did you know Richard?
他24岁在牛津拿到博士学位
Got his doctorate from Oxford when he was 24.
斯托克很有头脑
Stoker sure had the brains.
是啊  看看印蒂雅
Yeah. Just look at India.
又见面了
Hello, again.
你知道你为什么不爽吗
Do you want to know why you feel at a disadvantage right now?
因为我之前都不知道你的存在
Because I didn't know you existed until today?
因为你站得低
Because you're standing below me.
你和我爸爸很像
You look like my father.
很遗憾
I am so sorry.
你也失去了亲人
It's your loss too.
大概一分钟以内  你妈妈会告诉你
In about 60 seconds, your mother's gonna tell you...
我要在这待一段时间
...that I'm gonna be staying here for a while...
但我希望这是你的决定
...but I want it to be your decision too.
为什么
Why?
因为
Because...
这对我来说很重要
...it's important to me.
花园很棒
This really is a beautiful garden.
土壤
The soil...
松软
...is so soft.
适宜挖掘
Good for digging.
我不知道你用意何在
I'm not exactly sure what you're driving at.
我不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
我是唯一一个知道所有事情的人
I am the only one who would know anything about it.
我做了你让我做的事情
I did everything you asked of me.
我每年都来通知你
I kept you informed every year.
我一直是你的眼睛  耳朵  左右手
I was your eyes, your ears, your hands all this time.
你现在就像用尿布的小娃娃
You're acting like you're in diapers now...
从你是孩子起你就那样了  我受够了
...and you've done this to me ever since you were a child. I'm tired of it.
-我受够了  -好了
-I am tired of it. -All right.
加里克夫人
Mrs. McGarrick?
她去哪了
Where is she?
我也没见着
I haven't seen her yet.
早上好
Good morning.
丧葬礼仪大全
下午了
It's afternoon.
是啊
I guess it is.
你可不可以
Do you think you could--?
好姑娘  谢谢
That's my girl. Thank you.
你今天打算干嘛
What are you doing today?
准备
Thought I'd...
拉上窗帘  停掉钟表
...draw the curtains, stop the clocks...
按下镜子  宅我屋里
...cover the mirrors and then retire to my room.
别这样
Don't be morbid.
别穿这裙子了  这什么裙子
Get rid of that dress. What is that?
丧裙
It's my mourning attire.
出去转转怎么样
Why don't we get out of here?
逛逛街  吃吃冰淇
Go shopping. We could get some ice cream.
在维多利亚时代  寡妇要为丈夫哀悼两年
In Victorian times, a widow was expected to mourn her husband for two years.
至少
At least.
-印蒂雅  -在中国古代
-India. -But in Ancient China...
要在坟墓边盖个茅草屋  啥事不干住三年
...they built a straw hut beside the grave and lived there for three years doing nothing.
我们去吃吃冰淇林  呼吸呼吸新鲜空气
You and me, ice cream, fresh air.
来嘛  你老是跟他去打猎
Come on, all these years of hunting trips with him...
我只要求这一个下午而已
...and all I'm asking for is one afternoon with me.
你爸爸也希望看到这样的
That's what your father would have wanted.
你知道你爸爸和我总是不亲近
You know, your father and I weren't always so distant.
我怀念他
I miss when he was...
年轻的时候
...young.
美国护照
印蒂雅
India!
成熟的香气
Mature aroma.
年份很好
You chose a good year.
你不能和年份尚浅的酒比
You can't compare it to a younger wine.
丹宁酸太多
Too tannic.
还没准备好被打开
Not ready to be open.
你应该加入我们  印蒂雅  敞篷车
You should have come with us, India. Oh, the open top...
外面的空气  太棒了
...the air. It felt so good.
半路查理叔叔给你买了冰淇林
We stopped and Uncle Charlie got some ice cream for you.
一个巧克力  一个香草
One chocolate, one vanilla.
你喜欢吗
Did I get it right?
我喜欢漩涡混合的
I like the swirl kind.
你可以自己混合  懒姑娘
You can make the swirl yourself, you lazy thing.
加里克夫人呢
Where's Mrs. McGarrick?
不在这
She's still not here.
什么  那我们吃什么
What? What are we supposed to do?
我厨艺不好
I'm not much in the kitchen.
我会一点点
I can cook a little.
不用你做
No, you don't have to do that.
我很乐意
I'd love to.
查理  你到底是谁
Charlie, who in the world are you?
印蒂雅  把这放到冰柜里好吗
India, would you take these down to the freezer, please?
按叔叔说的做
Do as your uncle tells you.
-谢谢  -谢谢  印蒂雅
-Thank you. -Thank you, India.
下面很冷吗
Too cold down there?
不会
No.
以前理查德
You know, there was a time...
也会这样做饭
...Richard used to cook meals like this.
是吧  印蒂雅
Wasn't there, India?
哦  那会儿你还没出生呢
I'm sorry, of course. That was before you were born.
你在哪学的厨艺  查理
Where did you learn to cook like this, Charlie?
跟着雅克恩夫人学的
Madame Jacquin.
她在图卢兹开了家米其林星级餐馆  叫L'Institution
She ran a Michelin-starred restaurant outside of Toulouse called "L'Institution."
一个女厨子
A female chef.
在她的观念里  没有女人会的事情
In her opinion, there was nothing a man could master...
男人学不会的
...that a woman couldn't make.
什么意思
What do you mean?
用法语说听上去更好
It sounds better in French.
回家路上我说了吗  你法语口音很赞
Did I tell you on the way home? Your French accent is perfect.
这要归功于我受过的一流的教育
One of the perks of a first-class education.
即便余生都被关在这间屋子里
I could stay locked up in this house for the rest of my life...
我依旧可以说一口漂亮的法语
...yet still speak impeccable French.
我知道你不打算一辈子困在这间屋子里
I know you're not gonna spend the rest of your life locked up in this house.
你平时都干嘛  我想了解我的嫂子
How do you spend your days? I want to know my brother's wife.
不知道从何说起
Oh, I don't know where to start.
查理  你都没吃东西
Charlie, you didn't even touch your food.
你在我们的食物里下毒了吗
Did you put poison in the food just for us girls?
但是印蒂雅吃光了
But India ate everything.
像舔过的一样
Practically licked it clean.
很高兴你喜欢吃
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
我能拿点别的给你吗
Now, can I get you anything else?
冰淇林怎么样
Maybe some ice cream?
不
No.
要说  不  谢谢你
"No, thank you."
我是说  不  谢谢你
I mean, no, thank you.
你想晚饭后给我们弹首歌吗
Would you like to play something for us after dinner?
我不想
I don't think so.
你呢
Would you?
印蒂雅
India.
我是说  不  谢谢你
I mean, no, thank you.
你为什么不告诉我我还有个叔叔
Why didn't you tell me I had an uncle?
我自己都不了解查理
Because I barely knew about Charlie myself.
我认识你爸爸没多久他就环游世界去了
I mean, he's been traveling the world for as long as I've known your father.
他以前和我说
You know, he used to say to me:
不回家的家人哪叫家人
"What kind of family is family that never comes home?"
别讨论理查德了  失陪
Let's stop talking about Richard. Excuse me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
1994年
1994.
你出生的那年
The year you were born.
你想干嘛
What do you want from me?
和你做朋友
To be friends.
我们没必要做朋友
We don't need to be friends.
我们是家人
We're family.
全神贯注地观察需要时间
It takes time to observe attentively.
等待我们的眼睛
Wait for the moment that our eyes...
最终穿透物体的内部
...finally penetrate the inside of the subject.
看  马弗
Look, Marv...
看到那些花儿了吗  它们悬挂的样子
...see that flower? The way it just hangs there?
我的眼睛穿透了你的内在
My eyes are penetrating the inside of you.
仔细观察  你会注意到这个植物
Observe carefully and you'll note that this plant....
看看皮茨
Check out Pitts.
我想让你真正的
I want you to really....
皮茨
Pitts.
有事吗  费尔德曼先生
Yes, Mr. Feldman?
有什么要和大家分享的吗
Is there something you'd like to share with the rest of the class?
有啊
Yeah, I've got something I'd like to share.
和印蒂雅有关
With India.
太迷人了
He's gorgeous.
回来
Come back.
妈妈
Mom?
要下雨了
It's going to rain.
放松
Relax.
这样
There.
手指弯曲
Curl your fingers.
不是
No.
看着我  看到了吗
Watch me. You see?
我在教他弹琴
I'm teaching him piano.
查理叔叔完全是个初学者
Uncle Charlie is a complete beginner.
去换个干衣服  和我们一起玩
Put on some dry clothes and come play with us.
冲个热水澡不然要感冒了  快去
Why don't you take a hot shower first or you'll catch a coId. Come on. Here.
早上好  小宝贝
Good morning, sweetie.
查理昨天清理了球场
Charlie cleared off the court yesterday.
我们正要过去
So we're just gonna walk on over.
你不想一起来吗
You don't want to come, do you?
你好  印蒂雅
Hello, India.
我拿了理查德的皮带
I took one of Richard's belts.
他衣服有点大
His whites are a little big.
准备好了吗
Ready?
走了
Let's go.
印蒂雅
India?
是我呀
It's me.
来给金姨一个拥抱
Come and give your Auntie Gin a hug.
-你什么时候来的  格温多琳  -4点左右
-What time did you get in, Gwendolyn? -Around 4.
好吧
That's right.
你什么时候走
And when do you fly out?
看情况
That remains to be seen.
我本来想待个一两天
I'd originally planned to stay for only a day or two...
现在在考虑是不是要多待几天
...but now I'm thinking I should stay a bit longer.
多陪陪印蒂雅
Spend a little quality time with India.
对她真好
How nice for her.
-查理  -金姨
-Charles? -Auntie Gin.
你来这多久了
How long have you been here?
不长
Not long.
我们很感激他能放下欧洲的事情赶过来
We're so grateful that he's taken time away from his commitments in Europe.
-欧洲  -是的
-Europe? -Yes.
伊维  饭后我们聊聊吧
Evie, dear, after dinner, I was thinking perhaps you and I could talk.
-我们正在聊呀  -单独的
-We are talking. -Alone.
-关于什么  -比方说理查德
-About what? -Like Richard, for instance.
-理查德  -是的  伊维  理查德
-Richard? -Yes, Evie. Richard.
我侄儿  你亡夫
My nephew, your late husband.
我没那么快就忘掉他的名字
I don't think I'll be forgetting his name any time soon.
当然不会  我是想有没有什么要安排的
Of course not. I just thought there might be arrangements to be made.
都安排好了
Things to be settled.
我们律师说了都和你无关  你不在遗嘱里
Our lawyer has said none of this has anything to do with you. You're not in the will.
不是这个  我是说一些不一样的事情
No, dear, I mean something entirely different.
比方说
Like, for example...
聊聊你和查理这样住在这里
...maybe we could talk about your living here with Charlie like this.
指责我  金姨倒是一点都不害羞
Auntie Gin isn't shy when it comes to expressing her opinions about me.
就像理查德向我求婚时候
Like when Richard asked me to marry him. What Auntie Gin might be surprised...
金姨可能很惊讶那些流言蜚语一点都没被听到
...to learn is that those opinions are neither wanted, needed, or appreciated.
-伊维  -你到我家  指责我
-Evie-- -You come into my home and attack me...
在这种时候
...at a time like this.
伊维
Evie--
我觉得金姨不是那个意思
I'm sure Auntie Gin didn't mean anything.
你不是那个意思吧
You didn't mean anything by it, did you?
没有
No.
当然没有  亲爱的伊维
No, of course not, Evie dear.
你们两个饭后都不给我们弹个曲吗
Now, would either of you two like to play something for us after dinner?
-不  谢谢你  -不  谢谢你
-No, thank you. -No, thank you.
晚安  金姨
Good night, Auntie Gin.
别在意伊维  她就是太累了
Don't mind Evie. She's just tired.
你住哪里
What was the name of your hotel again?
-比尔提默  -比尔提默
-The Biltmore. -The Biltmore.
也许我们可以一起吃早餐
Maybe we could have breakfast together.
-就我们俩  -不一定
-Just us girls. -Oh, I'm not sure.
-送到比尔提默  -我早上会头疼
-Can you take her to the Biltmore Hotel? -I'll probably have a headache in the morning.
-慢点开  -金姨  今晚留下来
-Drive carefully. -Auntie Gin, stay the night here.
今晚我很开心
You made the evening much nicer.
谢谢  亲爱的
Oh, thank you, dear.
但是我这个老女人要时间休整  晚安  孩子
But an old woman needs time on her own to recover. Good night, sweet child.
打给我
Call me.
比尔提默附近有其他酒店吗
Are there any other hotels in town besides the Biltmore?
食物紧缺的时候  即便是亲人也没意义
Even family ties have no meaning when food is scarce.
这只知道在打猎中没有哥哥的份儿
This one knows there is no room for his brother in the hunt.
手足之争看似残酷  实则是适者生存
While this sibling rivalry may seem cruel, in the end, it is for the best.
每一天的打猎都使得鹰更成熟
Each day in the hunt brings the eagle closer to maturity.
它自己的雏鹰
--and chicks of his own.
最有耐心的捕食者  黑鹰能盘旋四个小时
The most patient of predators, the black eagle can circle for hours...
等待最佳时机  给予致命一击
...waiting for the perfect moment to strike.
鱼类给它正在成长的身体提供很多营养
The fish will provide much needed nourishment for her growing chicks.
我想确认下有没有人打进电话
I was wondering if anyone had turned in a cell phone.
可能登记时漏掉了
I think I may have dropped it when I was checking in.
你确定吗
Are you absolutely certain?
好的  等等  我要拨出按哪个号码
All right. Oh, wait, wait. What number do I have to press to dial out?
9  好的  我也这么觉得
Nine. Yes, I thought so.
宾馆
晚上请按铃
来吧
Come on.
山上可容不得胆小鬼
The mountains are no place for the faint of heart.
陡峭地形和严寒气候
The steep terrain and harsh climate make a challenging climate...
对于即便是最强大的动物都是挑战
...for even the strongest of species.
翅膀就代表自由
--wings are freedom.
虽然鹰更愿意自己找寻配偶  帮帮忙也没什么不对
--while the eagle prefers to find its own meals, there is nothing wrong in having a little help.
自然界的任何优势都是天赐  剩下的
Any advantage in nature is to be appreciated, and what the left....
对于明天要继续捕猎的饥饿的鸟类来说是一场丰盛大餐
--a hearty meal for the hungry bird who lived to hunt another day.
13磅重  翼长7尺
--thirteen pounds and a wingspan of nearly 7 feet.
你说你住比尔提默酒店的
You said you were staying at the Biltmore Hotel...
可是你在这
...and yet, here you are.
我打了出租车公司的电话
I even had to call the cab company.
被捕食者没有预料到捕食者会在高空一直盘旋
--prey does not suspect the hunter is circling high above...
出其不意攻其无备
...and is taken completely by surprise.
-嘿嘿  看看谁来了  -开玩笑呢吧
-Hey, yo, yo. Look who's here. -No kidding?
-是吗  真的吗  -是吗
-Is it--? Is it true? -Is it?
米德本高中
拿着
Yo, check this out.
-我跟你说  她会说话  -试试看
-I'm telling you, she can talk, bro. -Well, let's find out.
-怪人  -好啦
-Oh, creepy, man. -All right.
斯托克
Hey, Stoker.
-斯托克  -去哪
-Hey, Stoker. -Where you going?
跟你说话呢
I'm talking to you.
还是你叫斯卓克[按摩师  这里是双关]
Or do you go by Stroker now?
因为我听说你妈妈和
Because I hear that's what your mom's been doing...
你叔叔干的那事
...to your uncle.
你是不是也参与了
You been getting in on that?
有话要说吗
What did you say?
-她说话了  -你说什么
-She speaks. -"What did you say?"
你听到了  斯卓克
I think you heard me, Stroker.
再说一遍
Say that again?
好吧  你最好小心点  斯卓克
All right. I think you'd better watch your step, Stroker.
你知道惹恼了我有什么后果吗
You know what happens to little girls who mess with me?
看好
Watch this.
怎么样  贱人
What's up, bitch?
怎么样
What's up?
-怎么了怎么了  -天哪
-Hey, come here, you all right? -Oh, my God.
还好吗
You okay?
够了  皮茨
All right, Pitts. That's enough.
滚开  维普
Get out of here, Whip.
玩蛋去  混蛋
Follow the bouncing ball, jackass.
别惹她
She's not interested.
走了走了
Dude, let's just go.
好吧  就像我想在这贱人身上浪费时间一样  走了
Yeah, like I enjoy wasting my time on this bitch, anyways. Let's go.
-怪人  -抱歉
-Freak. -Sorry about that.
他是混球  别理他
He's an A-hole, okay? Just ignore him.
你去哪
Where you going?
下面冷吗
Too cold down there?
印蒂雅  把这些拿到冰柜里
India, would you take these down to the freezer, please?
你待得时间太长了
You stayed longer than I thought you would.
该走了
You probably need to move on.
你想我走吗
You want me to leave?
得了吧
Come on.
你可以回雅克恩夫人身边
You could return to Madame Jacquin.
跟我跳一曲
Dance with me.
我老是跟不上节奏
I always end up leading.
跟着我  伊维
Well then, lead me, Evie.
你知道
You know...
对我而言
...for me...
你是谁不重要
...it doesn't matter who you are.
我也是这样觉得的
I feel the same.
是吗
Really?
对我而言  我是谁也不重要
It doesn't matter who I am for me, either.
维普
Whip.
我觉得
I just thought I....
我没来过这
I've never been here before.
开什么玩笑
Yeah, no kidding.
明天见
I'll see you guys tomorrow.
玩得开心
Have fun, bro.
那
So....
想进去吗
You wanna go inside?
还是你想去哪
Then where would you like to go?
印蒂雅·斯托克  米德本全A生
India Stoker, Middlebend straight-A student...
半夜三更去瑞克斯的停车场
...hanging out in the parking lot at Rockets?
这不是你风格
Doesn't really seem like you.
你不懂
Not that you would know.
是啊  我不懂
Well, I.... I guess you're right. I wouldn't.
就是
It's just that....
是
Yes.
我知道你什么意思
I know what you mean.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
什么意思
How's that?
就像在不知道被拍下来的照片里
Have you ever seen a photograph of yourself...
看到自己
...taken when you didn't know you're being photographed?
看向镜子时看到的天使
From an angle you don't get to see when you look in the mirror.
你就在想  这是我
And you think, "That's me.
那也是我
That's also me."
你
Do you...?
你知道我在说什么吗
Do you know what I'm talking about?
我想我知道
Yeah. I think I do.
好吧
Well...
这就是我今夜的感觉
...that's how I feel tonight.
你对你自己感到惊讶吗
So you're surprised at yourself?
你不害怕被人碰了
You're not afraid of being touched anymore?
莫负好时光
Please don't spoil it.
操
Holy shit.
大家都说你是个疯子
Everyone said you were crazy.
他们什么都不知道  对吗
But they have no idea, do they?
我要回家了
I wanna go home now.
让我走
Let me go.
休想
No, you don't.
你开了这扇门  你就得走过去
You opened this door, and now you're gonna walk through it.
安静点
Quiet.
待在那
Hold still.
不疼的
This is not gonna hurt.
操
Shit, what--?
停下  停下  停下
Stop, stop, stop.
弄痛我了
I broke my--
庆幸我带了你爸爸的皮带  我的太短了
Glad I borrowed your dad's belt. Mine would've been way too short.
-操  -交给你了
-Shit-- -All yours.
-我受伤了  操  -闭嘴
-I'm seriously hurt. Shit. -Shut up.
印蒂雅  停下
India, stop.
印蒂雅
India.
停下  停下
Stop. Stop.
我要杀了你
I'll kill you.
我不会
I don't give a fuck--
打给我
谁
Yes?
我能进来吗
Can I come in?
现在几点了
Well, what time is it?
帮我梳头
Would you brush my hair?
我要睡了
I was just going to bed.
那我帮你梳
Then I'll brush yours.
你穿了我给你买的睡衣
You're wearing the nightgown I bought you.
今夜我感觉像穿了丝绸
Tonight I felt like wearing something silk.
就我有印象以来  我没帮你梳过头
Now that I think about it, I never brushed your hair...
是吧
...did I?
你太忙了
You were busy.
忙什么
With what?
我不知道
I don't know.
你和你爸爸老是去打猎
You and your father were always on your hunting trips.
你们源源不断地带死鸟回来  我怎么处理得完
How could I compete with all of those dead birds you constantly brought home?
今天我看到你在餐厅了
I saw you in the dining room today.
我不知道你怎么想
I don't know what you think you saw...
但是什么都没发生
...but nothing happened.
你走路好轻  我都没听到
You were so still, I never even heard you there.
爸爸教我的
Dad taught me that.
打猎
Hunting.
伺机而动
To wait.
保持安静
In silence.
我们不需要吃饭喝水
We wouldn't need food or drink.
我们能观察一切
We would watch everything.
树枝晃动
The patterns of tree branches spreading out...
树影婆娑
...the thousands of shapes clouds make.
我能在五小时内数出树叶的数量
I could count the number of leaves on a tree in five hours.
我一直以为爸爸爱打猎
I always thought Dad liked hunting.
但是今夜我意识到  他是为了我
But tonight I realized he did it for me.
他曾说  有时候你要做点坏事
He used to say, "Sometimes you need to do something bad...
来避免做更坏的事
...to stop you from doing something worse."
明天我要去做头发
Tomorrow, I'm gonna go to the hairdresser...
先要清理你爸爸的工作室
...after I clean out your father's study.
1988年  理查德17岁查理8岁乔纳森2岁  我的三个小鬼
Richard (17), Charlie (8), Jonathan (2) My 3 little monsters in a rare, quiet moment 1988
1989年  理查德18岁查理9岁
Richard (18), Charlie (9) 1989
克莱顿郡06003  印蒂雅·斯托克收
India Stoker 101 Nicher Hill Road Middlebend, Chayton County CT 06003
亲爱的印蒂雅  生日快乐
Dear India, happy birthday.
你今天5岁了  我希望我能来你的生日趴
You are 5 years old today. I wish I could be there for your party...
但是叔叔正在非洲给杂志拍照片
...but your uncle is far away in Africa taking pictures for the magazine.
最亲爱的印蒂雅  我现在在佛罗里达给你写信
Dearest India, I'm writing this letter to you from Florence.
昨天我绕着大卫像  他被吊了起来
Yesterday, I circled Michelangelo's David for hours. He carries a sling.
他的束带武器举过左肩
His belted weapon over his left shoulder.
-你是我唯一最亲的侄女  -我安静隐形的伙伴
-You are my dearest and only niece. -My silent and invisible partner.
这是我们共同学习的课程
And these are the lessons for you in our many chapters together.
-亲爱的印蒂雅  -再次生日快乐
-Dear India. -Happy birthday again.
我想念你第一颗牙长出来的时候
I've missed your first teeth coming out.
我看不到你嘴角的酒窝  和他们如何抚养你长大
I'll never see the holes in your smile or how they will fill in as you mature into a young lady.
来自圣埃蒂安的问候  这里的人见面礼都吻双颊
Greetings from Saint-Ètienne, where everyone I meet insists on kissing both cheeks.
-习惯是拥抱和亲吻  -我想你也觉得不舒服
-This custom of hugging and kissing. -I think you, too, would find this uncomfortable.
如果我发现是拥抱你  也许会破个例
If I found it was you in an embrace, I could make an exception.
-你会吗  -情人节快乐
-I wonder if you would, too. -Happy Valentine's.
-万圣节快乐  -圣诞节快乐
-Happy Halloween. -Merry Christmas.
-我从来没收过信  -你的消息藏在星星里
-Though I never receive a letter.... -I see your messages in the stars.
或者是我听的音乐里
Or in the music I hear.
流落他乡一个孤独男人的呓语
It is a whistling tune from a lonely man wandering in a foreign land.
事物发展到鼎盛时  我能强烈地感觉到
I sense things so acutely until it becomes almost too much.
不知道你是否也一样  人生艰难
I wonder if for you, too, life is made difficult by--
你能听到别人听不到的  看到别人看不到的
The fact that you can hear what others cannot hear, see what they cannot see.
我知道有一天你会与众不同  印蒂雅  你已经是了
I know that someday you'll be very special, India, and you already are.
-我知道你内心很孤独  -因为你是独一无二的
-I know inside you feel some loneliness. -Because you are the only one.
请相信我与你同在  因为我们流淌着同样的血液
Please know that I am with you as we share the same blood.
今夜我入睡时想着你已长大  冠以我们的姓氏
Tonight, I'll fall asleep as I try to imagine that you'll grow up and take over our name.
我多想见你
How I want to meet you.
-爱你的查理  -爱你的查理
-All my love, Charlie. -All my love, Charlie.
克劳福德邮局[美国西部]
Crawford Institute Box 6292 Crawford, PA 19086
生日快乐
Happy Birthday
正在为您接通米德本警长非紧急电话
You've reached the Middlebend Sheriff's Department non-emergency number.
如果紧急  请拨911
If this is an emergency, please hang up and dial 911.
如果不是  请等待接线员
Otherwise, please hold for the next available operator.
米德本警长办公室  有什么能帮到您
Middlebend Sheriff's Department, how may I help you?
你好
Hello?
我爸爸有一样的太阳镜
My father had the exact same sunglasses.
但只有开车时才带  一般放在车内储物箱里
He wore them only when he was driving so they were always in the glove compartment.
我以为连着车子一起融化了
Now I suppose they're all melted up, along with the rest of the car.
妈妈醒来前请离开
Please leave before my mother wakes up.
你不好奇理查德发生了什么吗
Aren't you curious about what happened to Richard?
我很好奇乔纳森发生了什么
I'm curious about what happened to Jonathan.
这是理查德事件不可分的一个环节
That's an inseparable part of what happened to Richard.
理查德总是带着乔纳森玩
Richard was completely taken with Jonathan.
那年夏天  乔纳森刚学会爬楼梯
That summer, Jonathan had just learned how to climb the stairs.
再来一次
Let's go again. Let's go.
每碰到梯子都要爬
He couldn't resist climbing any staircase he came across.
您的家人捐献这座房子给克劳福德已经20年了
It's been 20 years since your family donated this building to Crawford.
可能看上去很旧  可是查理的房间很舒适
It may look old now, but Charlie's room is still very comfortable.
你也知道  他想待在这
As you know, he was the one who wanted to stay here.
他坚持在今天离开
And he insisted on being discharged on this day.
今天
Today.
欢迎来我家
Welcome to my home.
离家在外的家
Away from home.
我们再次见面的时候
Until we meet again.
我为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
这是你最爱的车
It always was your favorite car.
我想你会喜欢纽约
I think you're gonna love New York.
我为你置办了一所公寓
I got you your own apartment.
看
You see?
我们不回你家吗
Aren't we going to your house?
你需要的都在这
Everything you need is in here.
我们为什么不回你家
Why aren't we going to your place?
我不能去见印蒂雅吗
I'm not gonna see India?
钥匙
Here are the keys.
一切都办妥了
I think you'll see that I've taken care of all the details.
干嘛这样对我
Why are you doing this to me?
真要我把你知道的事情再说一遍
Do I really have to tell you something you already know?
为什么我不能去
Why can't I go?
查理
Charlie.
为什么
Why not?
告诉我
Tell me.
你听好了
You listen very carefully.
这很重要
This is the most important thing.
-发生任何事  你打电话  -你还是爱我的
-If anything happens, you must call-- -You still love me, don't you, Richie?
当然  我爱你  查理
Yes, of course, I love you, Charlie.
现在我只能爱你少一点了  我不能让你
I just have to love you a little less now. I can't have you--
接近印蒂雅  接近我的家人
Near my India, my family.
我说
And I said:
但是我也是家人
But I'm your family.
不能带回家的家人算哪门子家人
What kind of family is family you can't take home?
-老天  -抱歉
-Jesus. -Excuse me.
老天  查理
Jesus, Charlie.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我没事  理查
I'm fine, Richie.
我没事了
I'm fine now.
谢谢关心
Thank you for asking.
查理
Charlie?
Oh, Charlie.
当然我还爱你  理查德
Of course, I still love you, Richard.
现在我也只能爱你少一点了
I just have to love you a little bit less now.
为什么是现在
Why now?
为什么现在回来
Why come back now?
我离开克劳福德的那天
The day I left Crawford...
你爸爸发生意外的那天
...the day your father had his accident...
是什么日子  你记得吗
...what day was it, do you remember?
是
Yes.
我记得
I remember.
什么日子
What day was it?
我18岁生日
It was my 18th birthday.
我一直在等待
I was waiting.
为了你
For you.
我做的一切
Everything I've ever done.
都是为了你  印蒂雅
For you, India.
生日快乐  印蒂雅
Happy birthday, India.
警长
Yes, sheriff.
我饿了  就去瑞克斯买炸薯条
I was hungry, so I stopped by Rockets for some fries.
我在停车场碰到维普  就去散散步
I bumped into Whip at the parking lot and we decided to go for a walk.
晚上  树林里很危险
At night? Those woods are dangerous.
我不怕
Oh, I wasn't scared.
和维普在一起我不怕
Not with Whip there.
他很强壮
He's so strong.
是啊
I see.
我们过得很愉快
So we had a very nice time.
然后呢
And then?
然后我回家了
And then I went home.
维普说他也回家了
I thought Whip said he was heading home too.
记得几点吗
Any idea what time that was?
大概
Well, that was....
你什么时候吃薯条的
When did you eat the fries?
什么
Excuse me?
你说你去那因为饿了
Well, you said you went there because you were hungry?
共度美好时光以后  你更饿了
And then, that is, after having a nice time, you would have become even more hungry...
如果你去吃薯条
...and if you went to eat some fries...
我也许能找到那会见过你的人
...I could find some people that can remember what time they saw you.
大概
I think I--
大概是
I think I must have been--
我肯定脸色发白
I must have been blushing.
因为是第一次和男孩子出去
It was my first time outside with a boy.
所以不想被看到
I didn't want to be seen.
你回家时是8点半
It was 8:30 when you came home.
PBS正在放游唱诗人
II Trovatore was playing on PBS.
是的  我回家时我叔叔在看电视
Yeah, when I came home, my uncle was watching T.V...
我就和他一起看
...so l watched it with him.
等等
Just one moment.
游唱诗人
II Trovatore.
那是什么  外国片
What is it? It's a foreign movie?
不是  威尔第的一出歌剧
No. No, it's an opera by Verdi.
-要我帮你写吗  -不用
-Would you like me to write it down? -I'm fine.
希望维普没事
I do hope Whip's okay.
他家人都急死了
Well, his folks are a mess.
不过我感觉他会回来的
Then again, I have a feeling that he'll turn up.
那个年纪的男孩子
Boys that age....
你也知道是什么样
Well, you know how they are.
我了解
I'm sure I do.
要是您听说了什么麻烦告诉我
You will let me know if you hear anything, won't you?
好的
Will do.
Okay.
保持联系
Well, I'll be in touch.
再会  警长
Goodbye, sheriff.
你家管家离开后还有联系吗
Oh, by the way, did your housekeeper ever get in touch after leaving town so quick?
没
No.
没有
She didn't.
就这么消失了真奇怪
Strange how people can just disappear on you.
他还会来的
He'll be back.
我们怎么办
What are we going to do?
现在我想可以去纽约了
I think we'll really love New York.
什么时候
When do we leave?
打扰
I'm sorry.
明晚
Tomorrow night.
-再做一次吗  -我饿了  先吃点东西
-Should we do it again? -I'm hungry. Let's eat first.
我总是在想为什么要那么早要孩子
You know, I've often wondered why it is we have children in the first place.
最后得出的结论是
And the conclusion I've come to is...
在某个时间节点上  我们意识到
...at some point in our lives, we realize things are....
我们的关系无法修复了
They're screwed up beyond repair.
所以要重新开始
So we decide to start again.
把过去恩怨一笔勾销
Wipe the slate clean.
重新开始
Start afresh.
所以我们要了孩子
And we have children.
书上这样说  你会做我不能做的
Little carbon copies we can turn to and say, "You will do what I could not.
你成功了在我失败之处
You will succeed where I have failed."
因为我们这次希望有个人是正确的
Because we want someone to get it right this time.
但是不是我
But not me.
就个人而言  我等不及看生活把你撕碎
Personally speaking, I can't wait to watch life tear you apart.
印蒂雅
India...
你到底是谁
...who are you?
你应该爱我的  不是吗
You were supposed to love me, weren't you?
来我房里一下
Come up to my room, please.
感谢你的演出
I enjoyed your performance.
印蒂雅  去收拾个小包
India, go and pack a small bag.
待会就走
We'll be leaving shortly.
我
I....
我是来道别的
I came to say goodbye.
我不能允许你这么做
I can't allow you to do this.
为什么不行
Why not?
一路上他察觉到了蛛丝马迹  但是他强忍着因为
There are little things one notices along the way, but one suppresses because....
因为
Because?
你怎么想
Why do you think?
爱
Love?
理查德爱印蒂雅
Richard loved India.
他不会在她生日那天开车去那么远的地方
He would never have driven so far away on her birthday.
除非他被人打电话叫去  对这个人他说不了不
Not unless, for some reason he was called away by someone he couldn't say no to.
金姨想找我谈谈你
Auntie Gin wanted to speak to me about you...
但那晚之后她再也没出现过
...but she never did come back after that night, did she?
人们同一时间
People disappear...
集体蒸发
...all the time.
来找我  放过我女儿
Have me instead, but stay away from my daughter.
她成年了
She's of age.
成什么年
Of age for what?
自己住这里  妈妈出门环游世界
To live in this house on her own while her mother finally travels the world.
你不是想去法国说法语吗
Don't you want to speak French in France?
你想说什么
What are you suggesting?
和我一起
Come with me.
印蒂雅
India.
过来看看
India, come here and look.
India, come here.
印蒂雅  过来 现在
India! Come here! Now!
赶时间吗
In a hurry?
知道自己开得有多快吗
Know how fast you were going?
你好
Pardon?
很快  警长先生
Effectively fast, Mister Sheriff.
这么快去干嘛
Effective for what?
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)
吸引你注意
To get your attention.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)